[Music]
hello and welcome to the react native
show podcast i'm mook as your host and
in this episode we'll dive deep into the
migration to react native we'll talk
about migration from native to react
native expanding react web apps with
cross platform availabilities
and the two main approaches to use in
migrating to react native greenfield and
brownfield
and what to remember and what to avoid
during the migration process and much
much more so stay with us let's get
started and introduce my guest
joining me today is mike hujak head of
delivery department
at call stack and great expert in
brownfield development hello mike
hey lukas thank you for the introduction
it's great to see you
oh yeah definitely
so mike
as we know as me and you know you are my
boss so
i'll let you start easy and i will ask
you an easy question
so your official title is head of
delivery and i must admit when i joined
call stack
several months ago almost a year i
didn't know what that really means so
maybe you can explain to our listeners
what are your daily responsibilities at
call stack
sure but before i do it i'd like to say
that it is my second time on the react
native show podcast but it's first time
i will be talking with you
and i'm super excited about it uh
because
we've been working together for a while
but we rarely have a chance to dive deep
into uh topics uh as technical as
migration to react native
so yeah thank you for the invitation
again
and getting back to your question uh at
call stack i'm managing team of
developers project managers and quality
assurance engineers
and on top of that i'm responsible for
ensuring the highest quality of our
service delivery
hence the title uh which means setting
quality standards best practices uh for
both development and
managing our projects
and even it
sounds a bit manager-ish i still have
many opportunities to touch the
technical stuff for example i provide
technical consultancy for our
key accounts and i do some open source
oh yeah definitely and i know i know
that you had a lot of opportunities to
talk about this subject that we are in
right now so migration to react native
brownfield development in react native
can you quickly summarize for me what
are your credential in this area why we
should listen to you
because i love react native and i'm good
at it
but jokes aside um i'm the person who
really believes in react native for me
uh it's an amazing framework that brings
a lot of business value and it's very
pleasant to work with uh
so um
on
the other hand uh it is just a framework
to enhance mobile development and i was
always very keen to understand what lies
under the hood uh that's why i've been
exploring native technologies from
objective c to kotlin
in order to understand how they solve
certain problems so i participated in
many web
web and mobile projects both react
native and native and i think i have a
good grasp of both strong and weak
points of these technologies
and
yeah based on that experience i created
a library uh called react native
brownfield which is a set of tools for
facilitation of the integration of react
native intonative apps uh and um yeah
it's very uh useful in uh such
migrations so i think that's that's all
in terms of my credentials yeah let's
put up in in the uh react native
brownfield library we'll talk about it
in the
in the following part but maybe we can
start in more structured way and sure
we can discuss uh from your experience
what are the main reasons our client
come to call stack to migrate their apps
sure so there are multiple reasons why
uh i think we can split them into
two main categories uh
first is addressing existing
uh and second is creating gains for the
future
so future proofing
yes
uh or basically creating
benef business benefits for the
future uh yes so in terms of first
category the stimulus
for such a decision is often
a thing that's bad for your business for
example the application has poor
performance and you lose users or
receive flow absolute ratings
and in such cases we can either try to
optimize the app or migrate it to the
new one
and while i'm a big fan of optimization
sometimes it makes no sense to deal with
existing code base and it's better to
create a new one
uh another example of the pain point
might be an increasing technical depth
that slowed down slows down the
development process
for for new features and makes
maintenance of the existing code base uh
a nightmare for developers
uh yeah but dealing with the paints is
not the only scenario uh to make such
decision and regarding the other uh
scenario which is uh
so maybe maybe i can add one point to
the pains that you mentioned and i feel
like in some project in some companies
there is this drive to deliver features
and to kill bugs but
the technical depth and like the quality
of the code base is often overlooked so
it
like it it is it does make sense to at
the same time migrate to some newer
better technology and at the same time
uh
increasing the quality of your code base
i think that is very important that we
don't lose this uh quality mindset
during the process
yeah definitely and addressing pains
doesn't exclude having gains so yeah
yeah but uh speaking about the gains
even if your app is working out well uh
you might think of ways to to improve it
from technical and business perspective
and trust me react native is really good
at it
so it speeds up speeds up the
development process
without
like introducing uh any additional
charges as developers may might use
same code based on ios on android and
maybe other platforms as well
so this minimizes development costs and
you can build a up in a fraction of of
time without affecting the quality and
that's a
key thing here
and i can tell you that if you do it
right every board will be happy with the
final quote and
yeah but yeah it's like
you're cutting down from two different
teams
to
one team with javascript developers with
some native uh
background instead of having two
different themes
uh
specified in native development for ios
and android so of course that that will
cut costs
yeah yeah definitely definitely and the
velocity itself or velocity of
programming itself might be
faster even if you compare platform to
specific platform to react native for
example
writing a feature in native aos might
take more time than native than writing
same feature in react native
it's yeah yeah
definitely
so
it's not a golden rule let's say but uh
in many cases it is like that
and yeah and another thing that i wanted
to mention regarding uh positives of
adopting react native is a possibility
of adding uh new platforms gradually uh
so i think one of the biggest selling
points of react native is having an
abstraction that is reusable between web
mobile desktop and other platforms
uh so
yeah it opens
uh another door because if you have a
application
let's say a purely web application
written in react you can convert it uh
to
react native
and
yeah and
it it doesn't take that much time so you
can do it in fairly short amount of time
and this way you can
expand uh the
expand to the market and operate uh on
different markets like uh i said mobile
desktop etc which opens up more
opportunities for the future
and when you mentioned desktop like a
few years ago uh electron came out right
and you could uh write react
applications for desktop but right now
we have react native windows and react
native mac os which allows you to more
or less use the same code base but your
application is native as on android and
us on ios so that brings you huge
performance benefits and
and other benefits as well
yes yes definitely uh so i think
electron is a good technology as well
but you can compare it to the
phonegap versus react native so you can
achieve
good results in both
but i always prefer to do things
natively
so react native for desktop react native
for mac os for windows
can help you achieve that
and yeah reusability that i mentioned is
also a big selling point
yeah so are there any other reasons why
you would want to
migrate your existing
web application mobile application
desktop publication maybe even
to react native
um yeah so i believe there are many but
one that comes to my mind is a good
developer experience as well i like
coding in react native for example when
i've been coding
in
native ios i had to rebuild
the
application each time i wanted to see
some changes i know that now it has
changed uh since
they introduced swift ui and the
developer experience is way better
but for me uh seeing the
changes uh live like with hot reload
it's
a nice thing to
to to to have at work
yeah definitely and you can streamline
the process for all of your team not for
just one for one platform you streamline
the process for
this one team that will create your
monorepo for example right this uni
application for all the platforms and i
think it is a
good
moment to point out that
with good developer experience comes
better velocity because your developers
are happy they're producing codes more
uh their producing codes faster and also
you can deploy your applications at the
same time with the streamlined um
release process using some like uh over
the internet tools and not using the
native uh upload to app store uh yes
solutions
definitely that's also a benefit and
another thing that comes to my mind is
open source community
uh it's amazing in react native i
totally love
this community love these people uh i
love how everyone contributes to the
greater good
and
it's simply pleasant to work in such
environment yeah this might be a good
time to pluck some like call stack
recruitment processes here if you want
to join call stack you will be able to
uh
work in open source and work within our
repositories and you you can also
help us out with our repositories not
joining call stack but just contributing
to our repositories
okay i think we have the um
the benefits of migration wrapped up so
where maybe we can move on to the other
part and the other part
i wanted you to ask
is
where do we even start with migration
process and what should people be
prepared for when preparing for
migration
uh
that's a very good question
so generally i suggest following a
top-down approach uh where we start from
what i call defining um the big blocks
such big blocks are in fact elements of
the migration process
or migration phases
so from my experience when i'm working
with such migrations i defined four
major components that every migration
should contain and those are first of
all business evaluation second of all
development planning and preparation
then implementation and then validation
and rollout
so basically this is how the process
looks like from a high level perspective
and
what
you need to do next is you need to break
it down into some smaller pieces
uh so also i
strongly recommend to approach it in
agile way
so it means that some of these steps
might be repeated multiple times on a
smaller scale
but answering your question precisely
before doing anything else
you need to know where you're at the
moment
so evaluate your starting point and um
the route to the beach uh is different
uh when you are in the
fire exclusive five-star hotel
with a beach view
and
it's different when you are in the
middle of the swamp
i really like this comparison
yeah but in both cases you can achieve
the same results
and feel the ocean waves on your skin
but
there is a difference in the process in
between
so
i have several supporting questions that
can help you evaluate the starting point
and
those are first of all
define what competencies
do you need in order to perform the
migration and then compare it to the
competencies you have in the team
because the gap will define
the requirements for
for the team
then think of platforms
so which platforms do you operate on at
the moment which platform do you want to
expand to
and then
consider
questions specific to the
let's say project itself so
let me interrupt you here like you said
before if you have a
web application written in react then
it's no brainer to re migrate to react
native but more generally if you have
your application written in something
else and it's all
up in the air
then your um
your
selection of technologies you might be
willing to work in is
different yeah
yeah yeah or maybe not the selection per
se but uh how to prepare for such
migration in terms of uh skills of the
team for example if you have react
developers you can train them to
operate in react native and
that's fairly easy process in comparison
to if you have
the native team and
then you need to teach them a new
paradigm which is also doable but then
you might think of strengthening your
team with some external resources to
to help
yeah
yeah but getting back to my initial
thought
then some questions or things to
tackle around the project so
see if you have feature maps and good
project documentation because it helps a
lot
do you have a complete design guidelines
do you have user stories
that describe the behavior of the app
is your code itself well documented and
last but not least do you have tests
that are agnostic from the
implementation
yeah and i feel like the the whole
selection you just mentioned the
documentation for for user stories for
your designs for your design language
for tests for code itself
some of those are nice to have let's say
but some of those are a must if you if
your project doesn't have some of those
you're
in big trouble
yeah yeah uh definitely so having green
lights in all of these areas uh will
help you succeed uh in the migration
will help you avoid the regression will
fasten the overall process uh however i
have to tell you that i rarely seen uh
all i rarely see uh all positives uh in
in all of the areas that that
i mentioned
but organize organizations still manage
to succeed uh so you just have to accept
that the process will be longer and more
fragile uh yeah and i i guess the the
process of migration itself can also
help with documenting right because you
are creating some of this from scratch
some of this you are re-engineering you
have to rethink this so this is a good
point to use this opportunity to
document at the same time
so you don't uh
yeah so you don't end up in the same
place like two years from now
yeah definitely
so a lot of stuff uh can be reused later
as you've mentioned and will help you
increase the overall quality of the
not only code ways but the projects
itself
so yeah at this point it's also good to
define some kpis or ctqs that you want
to maintain or improve in the final
project
can you can you
uh explain what kpi in ctq is
yes
not for me of course i know that you're
my boss i'm not saying that i don't know
that but maybe some of our listeners
uh sure sure apis are key performance
indicators uh so basically some metrics
that will help you uh track if you are
on track
and ctq's are
critical to quality and and those are
factors that
are most important for your end users so
usually you start with
interviewing your customers
defining uh what's important for them
listening to their voice and then
translating them to these factors
and uh it helps you uh have a
good uh overview or where on where you
are at
uh
shall we move on to
brownfield part so before we do that i
want to share some uh insider knowledge
that i got from wikipedia in the morning
today
um
so we are in the software development
environment we are talking about this
greenfield brown field approach and i
like until today i i i took it for
granted
because i didn't know really what that
what that meant like i i knew what that
meant but i didn't know uh where the
terms came from so uh i read up about it
and i know now and i can share this with
you and all the listeners so the terms
are coming from the property development
market in like great britain or
something
so if you go and you buy a new land and
this is a
green field
then it is easy to build upon it
and if you go and you buy land in the
inner city maybe this is some uh
post-industrial or something like that
with some buildings on it then it's
brownfield and
uh that entails that you have to clear
it up before you start developing the
land so this is the origin of greenfield
and brownfield development and uh
i guess uh
this is
like this is a good metaphor like it
fits very well with with uh like
application development as well
yeah yeah definitely yeah i also
was surprised back in the days when i
googled it
that it has its roots on civil
engineering uh but yeah like
long story short greenfield
is about writing from the scratch
and brownfield is about
writing on top of something that already
exists
yeah
so let's let's now focus specifically on
brownfield in react native and
we covered your credentials before and i
know that you've done tens of different
brownfield migrations and
is there a template that you use what is
your process if in
going in getting your heads dirty and
starting to do a migration to brownfield
okay so um specifically speaking in case
if you are
migrating from native applications to
react native like mobile applications
yeah
so
if you have an existing
native mobile app or actually apps
because usually companies target
at least ios and android
you can start to benefit from react
native without rewriting whole
application so we can start either by
adding some new features uh in react
native on top of existing application or
start replacing it to uh
start replacing some existing technology
with with react native and it's a fairly
uh simple process but it has powerful
implications as you can quickly cut down
the costs of feature development
you can write the feature once and use
it on every supported platform and of
course
from time to time you need to do some
platform specific adjustments but that's
not often a case
and speaking from
short-term perspective
you can start shipping your code way
faster than you would normally do it and
from the long-term perspective
as react native
code plays a bigger and bigger role in
your code base
your maintenance costs will be reduced
and mostly it's caused by two
to two facts first is that you will have
a fresh uh code base with no technical
depth and second uh that you will
need only one team to maintain uh the
coast yeah the the code base and develop
new features
um so
ultimately uh it's not um
only about the reduced development costs
but um also
if you don't need to get rid of existing
app uh i mean you don't need to
do it or you don't need to stop the
development uh and to start the
migration process so you can
in other words you can continue
generating revenue and keep developing
new features in the process
yeah and like the
benefit from like deployment perspective
is that this is the same application
that lives in the app store in the
uh
in the google store
so you don't have to do anything
different than you are
doing right now you can still use the
same system and and build upon it that's
great
yeah definitely um
also i i wanted to uh share with you a
few uh
words tips about how we as a coast tech
and do it
uh
but uh
before i do that uh i i wanted to tell
you that uh at the beginning uh the
process itself has a bit of entry
barrier uh to
to
to overcome
and what i mean by by that is that you
need to have a good grasp
of the javascript side of react native
as well as
its underlying native internals and in
order to be fully effective
you should have at least an average
understanding of native development as
you will work with the native code
to some degree at least
and what i'm trying to say is that it's
good to know the environment for example
um imagine if you would like to renovate
a house
so it's good to know
which walls can be destroyed safely uh
where electric installation is and how
hydraulics looks like
yeah yeah
definitely and like i think that uh
average understanding of native
technologies might not be enough maybe
average understanding of the android ios
systems sure
but then you have the whole inter native
internals of react native that you want
to use
and that is not well documented right
this is something that lives there you
can look at it
you can browse the repository
but it's not like
the lines itself uh
tell you
what is what that's supposed to do and
if you can remove this part and your uh
roof won't fall down
yeah yeah
but the
positive thing is i think is that once
you establish a good
brownfield integration to deal with the
uh
native codes that much uh what i try to
say is that you need to understand the
code in order to reverse engineer the
requirements uh or
in case the requirements are not well
documented of course uh but in general
it's good to have just an average
later but for the beginning uh the
process of let's say establishing good
brownfield setup uh might
require uh a bit more advanced knowledge
and might require a bit more uh let's
say diving into react native code base
uh itself
yeah uh yeah and also i wanted to
mention the other thing to consider uh
while doing such migration which is uh
the people perspective
uh so
maybe there is a team uh that is working
on the legacy code base and in most
cases there is
uh and such migration is a long process
and during that process uh you can focus
on preparing
the team to work on the new code base
or or maybe you would like to reallocate
them to some other project at some point
but in in both cases
they will have to operate within
the existing app
and text uh for some time
so
what i'm trying to say is that you don't
want to introduce tooling that will
decre decrease their productivity
and i'm mentioning that because we've
had such case in the past uh as when we
started migration we observed that the
native team uh the their performance
fell
and after searching to the root cause of
that i observed that they had to first
of all deal with the new tools like
node.js yarn or metro bundler that are
uh very common in uh js or react native
uh environment but for them it was new
yeah yeah
those are common but when you encounter
a new error from from metro bundler that
i cannot find this one file in your node
modules and like yeah it gives you like
several different lines of how that file
might be named and you're like
what like
i'm not the owner of this note modules
folder i don't know what's going on
there so yeah
this can be a pain
so uh
at some point uh they for example they
the team that's operated in the
uh
app that we added react native on top of
uh they did not know that they have to
install uh
dependencies run npm install run yarn
even though it was documented no
not everyone
has
read it and
it is a problem of course some trainings
help but you have to consider it
then the second factor is that they had
to observed changes in the repo that
they did not fully understand hence it
was harder to perform quality code
reviews
and
it's also important because they have
all the product and technical context
and uh
new changes no code reviews that that is
a problem at some point
yeah and
the
last factor was that they had to deal
with the increased build time as we had
to
build react native related stuff
and
each time they run the app
they had to do it over and over again
and the build time was increased hence
the developer experience
wasn't as good as as it was before yeah
at least for them
uh yeah so uh anyway we quickly realized
that there is a lot of uh things to
improve
uh at least
on on our side
and we started uh thinking on how to
overcome these issues and we came up
with a great solution that we have been
using in every project since then
so we created an engine to encapsulate
react native
js bundle assets native classes
and all of that into one file one native
artifact so native teams had to build
how to had to deal
only with the final product which uh
were either a aar file or xc framework
file
and they were able to uh interact with
it as they would interact with any other
native ui library yeah so
yeah i was gonna say it's like adding
manually library to your android project
you just put yeah exactly there and it
works
yeah or use some package manager they
could use maven or they could use
cocoapods uh things that they are used
to
so they didn't have to deal with react
native
environment their build time was
decreased to a number similar to what
they had before because we pre-built
everything that was related to react
native and finally they had a full
understanding of their code base
yeah
yeah yeah definitely
yeah and if you're interested about
these cases uh generally at callstack we
did multiple integrations like that in
the past so you can read about some of
them uh in the project section in our
website
oh yeah we have some case studies and we
have some articles and we have you on
react native show podcast number six and
we have you on the conference react
native eu so we will link all of that
materials
uh below this episode
sure
yeah and regarding
stuff from the podcast or stuff from the
conference
at some point we found that a lot of
these steps
are repetitive and we can
and we recreate the same code over and
over again
so we thought that it would be good to
extract it to an open source library and
this is how react native brownfield was
born
yeah
so
react native brownfield was introduced
in 2019 correct
yes yes yeah 2019 and since then we are
working on the new version
uh so can you tell us
who ordered it what was it you was it
you would some other folks at kolstek
yeah initially it was me with mike
grabowski
our cto
and
we initially thought of a set of
helpers to facilitate
integrating react native into existing
native apps
so you know it saves a lot of time as
you can omit several initial steps as
well as
decrease entry barrier for developers
who work on such project
and
at the beginning those steps usually are
first of all you start with preparing
some native classes that render react
native components within their bounds
then you load javascript
bundle you store an instance of react
native bridge into some singleton and
reuse it between
different
different components
and then you prepare javascript api to
uh let's say compose native and
javascript navigators because that's
often a case that you have to embed the
screen into
a native
navigation hierarchy and you do not want
user to notice that at some point there
are operating in react native yeah this
was actually the hard part when i tried
to visualize how brownfield works so
you can imagine that if you have a
mobile application written in native
android
you could do
react native
as like completely different set of
screens and like just link the two words
with just one intent one navigation
change and uh you are in the native now
uh you transfer to react native and you
browse in react native the hard part for
me is how do you
mix and match
the native with none
with react native which is still native
but with some bit of javascript on top
of it
and how do you maintain the whole system
this is uh this is really mind-blowing
for me i didn't do much of a brownfield
as you can imagine
sure uh yes so i will tell you about the
maintenance uh in a second so i will be
speaking about what's going on uh at the
moment at the in in react native
brownfield uh but before i do that i
will answer the uh part regarding the
integration itself which was covered in
the initial release of react native
brownfield nah so generally you don't
need to create
a separate intent you can embed react
native into fragment or an instance of
android
view
so uh basically you can embed a react
native component into native kirk which
helps a lot because then you have a
native navigator for example uh you uh
change you have navigations based on
fragments which is
i think the standard now for android
applications
and at some point you're under react
native within that and so what you need
to do basically is to toggle which
navigator is active is it the js one or
is it the native one
so react native brownfield has some
helpers to to do that
okay
uh yeah and i promised uh to talk about
the
maintenance part uh so let me tell you
about the next release of react native
brownfield which will include the
encapsulation engine from the case study
i mentioned before
as well as
many other killer features
so first of all we'll provide you with a
cli that lets you build
build an artifact with one comment and
plug it into your continuous delivery
process
and you will be able to publish the
artifact to any place you like so github
previous tab or things the native
package managers that i mentioned
cocoapods
maven jetpack
or
any place you want
so the cli itself and then another great
feature that we are building right now
is the generator of native components so
think of a react native components with
some annotation on top that is strongly
typed using typescript for example a
button
and it accepts some styles like text and
callback
and our generator will be able to create
a native button
a class a native class that will extend
ui button or android button
and it will accept properties like text
callback and styles in a constructor
and render your react native button
under the hood
and
thanks to
this engine you will be able to easily
create unified design systems that can
be consumed that whole organization you
know while keeping only one source of
truth
and
that source of truth will be written in
typescript plus react native
awesome
i like that idea
yeah uh me too
everyone's gonna love it i'm sure about
that this is a true killer feature so
where is it coming out
uh
yeah so about that i think that slowed
us down a bit or actually slows us down
but it is an important addition uh for
me personally uh is the adoption of
new react native architecture
so we will support turbo modules and
fabric renderer
although it increases the complexity of
the project and uh difficulty uh so
now we believe that having this support
is super important for the sake of
top-notch performance and we do not want
to release without that and that's why
it's delayed a bit but uh it's coming
this year
so i think it's understandable so you
will be
maintaining two different
implementations right the old renderer
and the fabric the
old native modules and then turbo
modules
yes for some time i think it's a
requirement because
we cannot resign from the old
architecture even though we'd like to
but until the community is ready for
say complete adoption of
a new architecture we will support both
okay
do you have anything to add to the
brownfield
migration to react native
uh no i think that's all if you're
interested in some more details um i
strongly encourage you to uh watch the
previous episode of react native podcast
episode
so
i was talking about react native
brownfield library per se
and you can hear some more details on
that
before we end this episode i was
thinking maybe we can take a detour uh
to talk some more about
the
web migration to react native or is it a
good idea and do you even call it a
migration or is it a conversion
and
our terms
brownfield greenfield even apply to this
kind of process
to some degree
so in this situation i would consider
two specific cases
first case is when you have an existing
web code base and you want to migrate it
to react and add the support of react
native and second is when you have
existing react application and you want
to expand to other platforms for example
mobile
and in terms of expanding to mobile
platform or any other platform that
supports react native
i would call it a conversion because
ultimately
this is what it is about
and i think this term is more suitable
in this case in the other case i think
it's rather a migration because you need
to adapt a whole new technology
um yeah okay
uh
is there anything else you would want to
do yeah sure sure i can tell you uh a
few words about the conversion from
react to react native because
that's the common case that we
deal with
at kostek
and
yeah specifically speaking of such
conversion and
maybe starting from
the time that is required to convert the
code base
it really depends on several factors
so you need to ask yourself again a few
starting questions so
see if your components are small and
modularized
see if your code is decoupled from
platform specific implementation
see if you use regular react dom
components for for example you use react
native web which would help a lot
but it's not a prerequisite
then how do you handle styling and how
different weapon mobile layouts are
yeah and answering these questions will
help you estimate the level of effort
required to
perform the conversion so the good thing
about that is that there are plenty of
tools that can help you implementing the
support to other platform
for example react native web that i
mentioned uh it exposes uh standard
react native core ui components that are
compatible with web and you can use them
instead of uh regular dom components
like d for p tags
if
i can give you uh
let's say
one tip about the the the whole
migration process here it would be to
divide and concur
so create small leaf components compose
them into larger ones
you can follow
the atomic design for example it will
drastically
help in the process itself
yeah
and
so i i was going to mention that react
native web is a huge library and there
are huge companies use using react
native web two i know are uber and
twitter
twitter uber web applications are built
using react native web
yes and not only that i can't call exact
names uh but many of our clients uh nda
this technology
and they are really happy with it and so
yeah i strongly recommend react native
web it's major uh it's nice to work with
and uh yeah it's cool but it doesn't
cover one thing that it is a challenge
to overcome in such a conversion
which is styling
so if you are using some css in js
solutions or inlands in inline styles
the amount of effort should be slight
uh but to be completely honest with you
i'm not a big fan of these solutions as
they often come with the costs like
performance overhead even though we have
our own open source library for css in
js code
yes but that one doesn't because
it
it's
used in the build time not in the
runtime so
if you use scenario it's great as well
uh
yeah but
if you are a dinosaur like me and you
like playing css or
scss
the amount of work will be significant
uh so but thankfully uh we have uh
some tools some open source tools that
helps in the this process like css and
react native uh we'll leave you a link
in the description
uh but generally it it helps a lot
uh yeah
yeah okay
uh
thank you mike i think that wraps it up
uh we talked about migrating from
uh native from native to react native we
we were talking about migrating from web
to react native from react native to web
as well because this is uh
like
that's the same process i guess uh we
talked about greenfield brownfield
solution i must say i'm really impressed
by your knowledge and by your expertise
uh
and now i know why you are the head of
delivery department
uh
that
covers like you say quality assurance
and development and and all that thank
you so much for joining me in this
episode of the react native show podcast
i was lukasz kludzinski
thank you everyone for joining as well
and see you in the next one
thank you a lot
no